KEMAL SERIT

Powercoders Participant | Accounting, Finance and Quality Management Specialist

Bartenheimerstrasse 12, 4055 Basel | 29.11.1986 | Residence permit B kemal.serit@powercoders.org | 078 783 00 70

GitHub | Learning Blog | LinkedIn

Languages: English (B1), German (A1), French (A1),

Turkish (mother tongue)

IT skills: Beginner: React.js, MySQL

Elementary: HTML5, CSS3, Java, Github, JavaScript

SUMMARY

In Turkey, I have a successful history in public finance management and quality management. I am a person with high discipline, motivation, hardworking, determined, team player, open to learning and never giving up. My personal vision; after this new career change that I made by moving to the field of IT to sign a very important software project that touches the lives of people around the world in the next 5 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/2012 – 06/2016

Quality Management Manager, Quality and Finance Management in an Organization of the Ministry of Interior, Istanbul, Turkey

 I prepared a technical specification according to international standards of many materials used by the public institution consisting of 200.000 thousand people. Scientific laboratory materials, computer and communication materials, electronic materials etc.

05/2011 - 06/2012

Budgeting and Finance Manager, Budget and Finance Management in an Organization of the Ministry of Interior, Ankara, Turkey

 During this period, I conducted a financially independent external audit of an important company. As a result of computer-based financial statement analysis, I revealed the unsuccessful management of the company management. I received a success award by the shareholders.

EDUCATION

09/2020 – 12/2020 Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich, Switzerland

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming

- Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

05/2020 – 08/2020 Ecap Basel - German Course A1, Basel, Switzerland

09/2019 – 03/2020 Neuchâtel Migration Reception Center Tête-de-Ran - French Course A1,

Neuchâtel, Switzerland

02/2019 – 03/2019 Hestia Hellas – Java Course, Athens, Greece



- Java Basics, Eclipse IDE, Object Oriented Programming Logic, Software Project Cycle.

09/2012 - 07/2016

Sakarya University Accounting and Finance Masters with Thesis, Sakarya, Turkey

- Two different scientific articles from scientific questionnaires I applied to 619 people were published in two different refereed journals.
- Serit Kemal, "Are Caspian Insurance Related to Individuals' Anxiety
 Levels or Demographic Characteristics?" Refereed Journal of the Institute
 of Social Sciences of Abant Izzet Baysal University 15.1 (2015).
- Serit Kemal, "Are the Anxiety Levels or Demographic Characteristics of Individuals Acquired with Fire Insurance?" Refereed Journal of Business Research 6.4 (2014).

09/2009 – 07/2016 09/2006 – 09/2011	Gazi University Accounting and Finance Masters with Thesis, Ankara, Turkey Anadolu University Faculty of Management- Department of Business
	Administration (4 Years), Eskisehir, Turkey
09/2004 –06/2008 Turkey	Gazi University - Accounting and Finance Teaching (4 Years), Ankara,
09/2000- 06/2003	Trade Vocational High School- Department of Accounting (Including 10 finger speed keyboard usage training), Istanbul, Turkey

ADVANCED VOCATIONAL EDUCATION

11/2012– 11/2012	Ministry of Interior Quality Management Expertise Course, Ankara, Turkey
09/2010- 05/2011	Ministry of Interior Finance Course, Istanbul, Turkey
11/2010- 12/2010	Ministry of Interior Orientation Course, Ankara, Turkey
02/2010- 09/2010	Ministry of Interior Executive Personnel Course, Istanbul, Turkey

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

02/2016-03/2016

Ministry of Interior Logistics Unit, Istanbul, Turkey

 Started a campaign to meet the clothing needs of children who had to stay in the dormitory because their parents were not alive. In this way, I led the team that met the school needs and clothing needs of nearly 100 girls. And I provided the link between official institutions.

CERTIFICATION

08/2020	EF Standard English Test (EF SET), Englisch B2 Certificate
10/2015-10/2015	Ministry of Labor and Social Security, Occupational Health and Safety
	Training, Istanbul, Turkey

AWARDS

09/2010–05/2016 A total of 26 awards (plaque, certificate of appreciation, money award), public institutions.

HOBBIES

Sudoku, cycling, reading books, listening to music, running, discovering new places, trekking, doing research on any subject. Acting, I acted in many theatrical drama activities, especially during university education. I have a great interest in numbers. I like to use statistical science to determine the relationship between data.

REFERENCES

Hussam Allaham, Powercoders Industry Lead, hussam.allaham@powercoders.org, +41 77 906 16 27